YOUR ADDRESS

■ 00000000000 | ■ thisis@fakeemail.com | ② github.com/themagicalmammal | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/themagicalmammal

## **Personal Profile**

A Master's student at the University of Leeds, undertaking the Data Science and Analysis course. Zealous about software engineering and with 1+ years of experience specialising in machine learning, python development, algorithms, and full-stack web development. Primarily, looking for Machine Learning/Data Engineer/Python Developer roles.

## **Education**

University of Leeds Leeds, UK

MSc in Data Science and Analysis

Sept 2021 - Current

- Head of School International Excellence Scholar
- · Working as a PAL Mentor
- Courses: Data Science, Programming for Data Science, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Statistical Theory and Methods, Learning Skills through Case Studies, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Statistical Learning

### **Madhav Institute of Technology and Science**

Gwalior, India

BTech in Information Technology

May 2016 - May 2020

- · Graduated with Distinction
- Selected for Industrial Visit among the top of the class

### **Atomic Energy Central School**

Indore, India

High School Apr 2014 - Apr 2016

- · Passed with Distinction
- Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

## Work Experience \_

### **Indian Institute of Technology**

Indore, India

Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - Aug 2021

- Collaborated with a four-person team to develop a CNN model that utilised YOLO as a foundation to improve the accuracy of ambient lighting conditions in the Mobile net architecture.
- Automated and optimised the data handling process for traffic signs, working with Ubuntu 20.04 did shell scripting, and employed other Linux tools.
- Significantly boosted the model's accuracy by 60%, which was yielding an accuracy of 70-78% under Indian street light. The older models, had an accuracy of 10-15%.
- Technical Skills: Python with PyTorch, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn, C++, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

### Raja Ramanna Centre for Advanced Technology

Indore, India

Machine Learning Intern

Apr 2020 - Sept 2020

- Build a model with a team of three that works with a Genetic algorithm and is portable for scheduling scenarios may it be a schedule for school, employee time sheet etc.
- Designed to be flexible to any case with low time complexity compared to the existing models which were only useful in specific scenarios.
- Produced everything from scratch and published the library on PyPi.
- Technical Skills: Python with GeneticAlgorithm, NumPy, Setuptools, Wheel, Twine, Git.
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

# **University Projects**

### The Relation between GDP and IMR

Leeds, UK

University of Leeds

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

- Analysing data from 1960 to 2020 and discover patterns in the data that show trends between Gross domestic product per capita, Infant Mortality
  rate, Literacy Rate, and Industrial Development.
- Study cross-sectional, longitudinal, and among various countries to find variations in trends and get the historical data to back up the change in the trend of our data.
- · Specific case studies were traced back to trends seen in the UK and how they affected the GDP and IMR.
- Technical Skills: Tableau, Overleaf, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

FEBRUARY 13, 2023

**IPL Analysis**Leeds, UK

University of Leeds Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- · Analysing data from 2008 to 2015 to discover patterns such as trends, correlations, and probabilities.
- · Finding the differences between the best teams and players in various fields, as well as their performance on the field and the opponents.
- Technical Skills: Python with Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Leadership, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

#### Study of the behavior of Serial Killers

Leeds, UK

University of Leeds

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

- Study of serial killers behavior with various motives such as convenience (did not want children or spouse), enjoyment, power, escape, or avoiding arrest.
- Finding patterns in their starting and ending ages (when they are caught) and other factors of killing, as well as how it varies with different motives.
- Technical Skills: R with ggplot2, tidyr, R Markdown.
- Soft Skills: Report writing, Logical Thinking, Critical Thinking.

## Skills\_

**Programming** Python (Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn. etc.), R(ggplot2), PHP, C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Łamber (Dyerleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Firebase, Git. Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

## **Achievements**

2019	<b>319/340</b> , Graduate Record Examinations (GRE)	India
2018	Elite, DBMS NPTEL Exam	India
2018	Elite, C NPTEL Exam	India
2019	Winner, Smart India Hackathon (SIH)	India
2014	Level 3, TablaNiketan Exam	India
2014	Level 1, National Talent Search Exam (NTSE)	India

## Interests\_

Cooking	I love cooking.	I am an expert in most	Indian-style coo	king, enjoy l	baking and	l making my own pi	zza.
---------	-----------------	------------------------	------------------	---------------	------------	--------------------	------

**Linux** Since 2017, I have been in love with Linux. I recently switched to Mac OS, which feels like a premium of Linux.

**Technical Writing** I write descriptive blogs about Linux some of them are on my GitHub and Medium.

Art I have always enjoyed drawing since I was a child. Recently, I have shifted to digital art mostly on Deviantart.

Video Games I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my switch.

**Swimming** I started swimming when I was 12. Going through submerged things while holding my breath was the most exciting part.

**Music** I enjoy almost all types of music may it be screamo, punk rock, bluegrass, pop, psychedelic, rap, and japanese.

## Languages\_

English Professional proficiencyHindi Native proficiencyBengali Bilingual proficiency